<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cancer on Gillian Chu</title>
    <link>https://gillichu.github.io/tags/cancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cancer on Gillian Chu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gillichu.github.io/tags/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CNAViz</title>
      <link>https://gillichu.github.io/publications/cnaviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gillichu.github.io/publications/cnaviz/</guid>
      <description>CNAViz: User-guided local and global copy-number segmentation for tumor sequencing data
(In submission)
Motivation: Copy-number aberrations (CNA) are genetic alterations that amplify or delete the number of copies of large genomic segments. Although they are ubiquitous in cancer and subsequently a critical area of current cancer research, CNA identification from DNA sequencing data is challenging because it requires partitioning of the genome into complex segments that may not be contiguous. Existing segmentation algorithms address these challenges either by leveraging the local information among neighboring genomic regions, or by globally grouping genomic regions that are affected by similar CNAs across the entire genome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CNAViz</title>
      <link>https://gillichu.github.io/publications/upp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gillichu.github.io/publications/upp2/</guid>
      <description>Motivation: Multiple sequence alignment (MSA) is a basic step in many bioinformatics pipelines. However, achieving highly accurate alignments on large datasets, especially those with sequence length heterogeneity, is a challenging task. UPP (Ultra-large multiple sequence alignment using Phylogeny-aware Profiles) is a method for MSA estimation that builds an ensemble of Hidden Markov Models (eHMM) to represent an estimated alignment on the full length sequences in the input, and then adds the remaining sequences into the alignment using selected HMMs in the ensemble.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>